You. my dear. have received
an offer of marriage.
A what?
From an incredibly
wealthy gentleman
with an old and
prestigious title.
Good heavens!
I do not know His Grace.
or any Grace. for that matter.
This family's happiness
is worth every sacrifice.
Then you mean to
accept the duke's offer?
Dearly beloved.
we are gathered here
together in the sight of God
to join together this man and
this woman in holy matrimony.
Is your name
really Persephone?
It is.
Did you not think to ask?
I had expected someone
rather long in the tooth;
So had I.
Give the poor girl a chance.
It's not her fault
you've ended up
with every man's
idea of a perfect wife.
24 hours into this
ill-conceived marriage
and my wife is already sobbing.
"Dear Persephone.
we've been home for two days now
and I am nearly
dead with boredom!
Athena spends all her time
practicing country dances.
I do not think she
will find a husband
dancing like she does.
No gentleman would
want to marry someone
who dances like a cow.
I am running
around like a heathen
and terrorizing
the neighborhood.
It's lovely.
I wish you were here so we
could be heathens together.
When can I come
explore your towers?
You did promise.
I will have my birthday
in London. Daphne says.
I will invite you.
If the duke wants
to come. he can too.
even if he never
did talk to me once
while I was at his castle.
Please write to me.
Be sure to put the
guinea under the seal.
Your sister. Artemis."
You seem in good
spirits this afternoon.
I've been reading a letter
from my youngest
sister. Mr. Windover.
We are practically
brother and sister;
we needn't be on
such formal terms.
Do you miss
your family. Harry.
being here as long
as you have been?
I consider Adam my brother.
Being here is being with family.
How is it that the
two of you are so close?
He is so hostile towards you.
Adam is hostile
toward everyone.
It is just the way he is.
Does he never show any
tenderness of feeling?
Not in the two
decades I've known him.
Then you forged a friendship
with someone who
was already adversarial?
Adam saved my skin.
I was something of a runt.
and the other boys
at Harrow found
that grounds for torturing me.
Adam put a stop to that.
They took orders from him?
They were afraid of him.
They still are.
Everyone is.
But he would've only been
seven or eight years old.
Seven.
Oh. he was a force
to be reckoned with.
By the time he was a
shell. he ran Harrow.
Shell?
The youngest year.
Some of the boys. now
grown gentlemen. of course.
still whimper when they see him.
To be so utterly terrifying
when he was only a child.
Well. it wasn't that. exactly.
He was.
still is.
remarkably intelligent.
And he is authoritative.
the kind of man
few people question.
Even at seven he was
very much that way.
And he is utterly unafraid.
There is nothing
that frightens him?
Nothing that intimidates him?
Mm.
Why won't he ever look at me?
What do you mean?
Never mind.
He never looks at you?
Hmm. that is out
of character for him.
Adam usually faces
problems directly.
I am a problem. then?
A poor choice of
words on my part.
A great deal has changed lately.
Adam does tend to get more.
I don't know.
prickly when he
has a lot on his mind.
So you're saying I
shouldn't give up yet?
If I'd given up on
Adam for being grumpy.
we wouldn't be friends.
How long did it take
for him to stop being
prickly with you?
He still is.
Adam would never admit it.
but he knows I
refuse to be bullied.
and I think he respects that.
He keeps trying.
But I think he
hopes it'll never work.
So he doesn't like people
who are intimidated by him?
He doesn't respect them.
That is a little different.
It is a great deal
different to Adam.
Adam likes his mother.
But he doesn't respect her?
Mother Harriet. I have called
her that since I was a boy.
has made something of a
hobby out of pitying Adam.
And he doesn't like that?
Ha. it frustrates him.
Frustrates him.
Mm.
If Adam does not like
people to be afraid of him.
why does he go to such lengths
to make certain they are?
I have my theories.
but Adam's motivations
are not a topic
I am willing to discuss.
I am attempting
to find my place here
and claim a degree of
equanimity with my new husband.
I need help if I am to have
any hope of understanding Adam.
Most people do not even try.
But he is worth sorting
out. Persephone.
I promise you.
he is.
He really never looks at you?
Something about
you has ruffled him.
Nothing ruffles Adam.
Stay.
Go around. walk past.
One more.
Jus' so. Yer Grace.
She's a bit skittish
this morning.
it bein' so cold an' all.
Haven't you a horse that
isn't skittish about cold?
Well. Atlas
behaves in the cold.
Who
named the horse Atlas?
His Grace did.
And His Grace does not
think it a ridiculous name?
It being Greek and mythological?
Named 'is own mount. Zeus.
That be one o' them
heathen gods an' all.
Such names are not
ridiculous for horses.
Then I had best search
the forest for a sorceress
to transform me into a horse
lest I spend the rest
of my life doomed
to a constant state
of ridiculousness.
You would make an
atrocious horse. Persephone.
On that. we can agree.
What brings
you out this early?
I was hoping to
attempt to ride again.
How long have you
been out of the saddle?
10 years.
10 years!
And you were going to
attempt to ride Alibi?
Ah. no. Yer Grace.
The Duchess were just askin'
if the filly were
ailin' or upset.
I was thinkin' Atlas would
be good for Her Grace.
That's a good choice.
Are you really going
to try riding again?
To be perfectly honest.
I'm not certain one
could accurately call
my previous experience riding.
Our neighbors. the Uptons.
allowed me to ride a pony of
theirs on occasion as a child.
If memory serves. it was aged
and did little more
than shift its weight.
Stay. stay.
She's calm an'
steady. Yer Grace.
She'll not hurt you.
May I feed her a carrot?
The Uptons' pony
was fond of carrots.
Well. perhaps the poor
thing waddled so much
because he was overfed.
That's it. calmer.
That's it.
If she and Atlas part company.
see to it that John has her
brought up to the castle.
Don't you even
want to see her try?
I've seen enough
people quit in my lifetime
without witnessing
the same thing again.
I think she'll surprise you.
Ey. .
Have them over?
Yeah.
You've had quite a
few riding lessons now.
Are you feeling more
confident in the saddle?
Quite a bit more.
Tomorrow I intend to attempt
to jump the castle wall.
Atlas doesn't know yet.
Eh.
Just my luck
that I'll miss that.
Miss it?
I am for Hawick
in the morning.
Are you certain you
couldn't leave tonight?
Do you go to Scotland often?
I have an aunt
and uncle in Hawick.
They're always asking
me to come for a visit.
And I am always
asking you to leave.
How is it that their
requests are adhered to
and mine are ignored?
Because I know you do
not actually want me to go.
I have never been to Scotland.
You live a stone's
throw from it now.
Perhaps you and Adam
could gad about
Hadrian's Wall sometime.
I do not gad about.
I have not ever
been to Shropshire.
though I hear it is beautiful.
I admit to being very
biased on the matter.
but I think it is the most
beautiful area of England.
All my family does.
Athena waxes poetic
about it quite often.
Evander's letters regularly
mention missing Shropshire.
Have you heard from either
of your young navy
brothers recently?
The last letter I
had from Evander
indicated the Triumphant.
the ship they are serving on.
was not far from Spain.
There's a great
deal of activity
in that part of the
world just now.
I worry over the
boys almost constantly.
And I worry about my
sisters. and my father.
About quite a few
people. truth be told.
Well. rest assured.
Persephone.
you needn't worry
about me while I'm away.
My aunt and uncle will fuss
over me more than sufficiently.
leaving you ample energy
for gadding about with Adam.
I do not gad about.
Good afternoon. Adam.
I will not intrude on
your solitude for long.
This has arrived.
and I wish to explain.
Please sit. Adam.
I'm fine.
I'm not asking for your
comfort. but for my own.
I have no desire to
strain my neck looking up
as you loom over me.
Now will you open the parcel?
You said you
wanted to explain.
After you open it.
You cannot ride without
a proper riding habit.
I ordered it because
you need one
and I did not think you
knew where to obtain it.
You ordered this for me?
I don't know that it is the
color you would have chosen.
But. well. blue
seemed a good option.
You'll need it when you ride
regardless of its color.
You must have great faith in
my ability to learn to ride.
Thus far I am proving
a very poor pupil.
Quite a bit better yesterday.
You watched me?
With Harry gone. I have
a lot of time on my hands.
Your boots will
take longer to arrive.
Well. you've ordered
boots for me as well?
Well. your house slippers
are hardly
appropriate for riding.
I haven't been
wearing slippers.
You might as well have been.
I don't know
what to say. Adam.
It's not necessary
for you to say anything.
I only wished to explain.
Thank you. Adam.
This is probably the most
beautiful thing I've ever owned.
And it'll be warm.
You chose a good
color. I do like blue.
Oh. I. um. I nearly forgot.
This has arrived
for you as well.
I shall leave
you to your letter.
Persephone?
There's been a battle at sea.
Near Cape Trafalgar.
Um. the Triumphant
sustained heavy losses.
Your brothers?
Linus's fate is unknown.
Evander is dead.
She's in pain.
and I can't do a
blasted thing about it.
I haven't the first
idea where to start.
When mother was distressed.
she just left Falstone.
Persephone hasn't left yet.
So. what do I do?
I don't want her
to be miserable.
I need her...
Duke's don't need people.
Mother has always preferred
being away from me.
Persephone will as well.
Adam?
Adam. I think I hear wolves.
I'm trying to be brave. Adam.
I need my family.
You didn't bring a coat.
You'll contract an
inflammation of the lungs.
Everyone in London will
accuse me of poisoning you.
You'll be warmer inside.
Look. with Harry still gone.
the castle will be quiet.
And you can find a private
spot to go and. uh.
and do whatever it is
you do after you cry.
I usually sleep.
And wake up with a headache.
Sounds awful.
Generally. I
can't help myself.
It's falling off of you.
You'll be warmer
if you just button it.
You really don't
want me to be cold.
I don't want you
to be miserable.
Adam.
You've missed your
riding lesson this morning.
I'm afraid I overslept.
And how is your head?
My head?
You said last night
that your head hurts
after you've been crying.
It does ache a little.
There is an
apothecary in Sifton.
It's quite competent.
I could send one of the
grooms for some powders.
I don't need any powders
just now. but thank you.
John has indicated
that Atlas can be saddled
whenever you would like to
have your riding lesson today.
I'm not sure
I'm up for a ride.
Are you certain you do
not wish for some powders?
I could have some here
before the weather changes.
Rest is what I need most.
But. again. thank
you for offering.
Yes.
Urgent
message for Your Grace.
Tell the stables to prepare
my swiftest traveling coach.
And send someone
to Sifton for Mr. Johns.
Yes. Your Grace.
Are you leaving. Adam?
Almost on the instant.
Tell Mrs. Smithson to prepare
Mr. Windover's usual room.
Is something the
matter with Harry?
He's taken exceedingly ill
at an inn between
here and Hawick.
What are you intending to do?
Go retrieve him. of course.
If the stables will ever
send my carriage. that is.
It looks like it might snow.
It's precisely why I wish
to make an immediate start.
But is it safe?
If the weather worsens. you
might become stuck on the road.
I can reach the
inn before then.
How will I know you're safe?
If I do not return tonight.
you can assume that I am
waiting out the weather
at whatever
flea-infested hostelry
Harry has decided
to take ill in.
I will assume no such thing.
Simply not returning
will tell me nothing.
You could just as
easily be half frozen
on the side of some road
or devoured by
wolves or ill yourself.
I've driven these
roads for years.
I've never once broken down.
You must promise
me you will be careful.
If you don't. I will worry.
Why would you worry about me?
Why wouldn't I?
No one worries
about me. Persephone.
Someone does now.
Don't.
I'm afraid I can't help it.
Like crying?
Worrying will probably give
you a headache as well.
Then spare me the headache
and promise me
you will be cautious.
I will be cautious. I promise.
Where is the owner
of this establishment?
I'm Smith.
What can I do for you. guv'nuh?
There is a gentleman staying
at this inn. Mr. Windover.
Where is he?
Huh.
How much is
knowin' worth to you?
Is that your way of
begging me pardon?
I beg no one's
pardon. Where is he?
Settle the cove's
bill. then I'll tell you.
His bill will be settled
in the usual manner.
upon departure.
Afraid I'll be adding
to the bill. then.
Inconvenience. you see.
But. iffen you're in a mind
to toss a few extra pounds in.
you might save yourself
some blunt in the end.
A few extra pounds?
What do you feel you
are currently owed?
Can't say really.
Goes higher all
the time. doesn't it?
Reckon a few shillings been
added since we've been talking.
Where is the gentleman
who's staying here?
I'll call your
account due. Hooper.
I ain't got a shilling.
A half-crown.
Where is the gentleman
who's staying here?
First door on
your right. guv'nuh.
Blast it. Hooper.
If you're dead. don't
expect me to eulogize you.
Even to tell me to
shut up one last time?
What instructions did
the physician leave?
Haven't seen one.
Was one not sent for?
I made repeated
requests. Your Grace.
But I was prevented
at every turn by-
Why did you not allow a
physician to be summoned?
This gentleman is clearly ill.
I ain't running
a charity. guv.
He'd nothing to
pay a doctor with.
And his manservant. there.
is poorer than he is.
So you left him
to grow more ill.
perhaps to the point of
endangering his life?
Poor people die all
the time. don't they?
How many have died in this inn
waiting for help that
was never going to come?
The sick and
dying don't fight back.
Makes it easier
to settle their bill.
By picking their
pockets. no doubt.
Adam.
Can we go back to the castle?
From the looks of you.
we'd do better to go
directly to a cemetery.
Likely a good idea.
Let's get Mr. Windover
to the carriage.
Of course.
How much do you imagine
you are owed by Mr. Windover?
Considering everything. I'd
settle up for five pounds.
Five pounds?
Nothing you have
provided or could provide
is worth a tenth of that.
I reckon you can afford it.
And do you demand
such exorbitant sums
from people who can't afford it?
Someone will always
walk away poorer. guv.
I'm just making
certain it ain't never me.
Your five pounds.
Here's hoping we can do
business again in the future.
We will.
You've taken Evander.
Please do not take
my husband as well.
Take him to his chambers.
Is Mr. Johns here?
Yes. Your Grace.
I told you I'd be careful.
I suppose I
should've believed you.
Yes. you should've.
You look cold.
I'm freezing.
You should change into
something warm and dry.
Mr. Johns will see to Harry.
Are you to be my
voice of reason. then?
Your hand is cold.
I'm. [clears
throat] my apologies.
If you'll excuse
me. I've been told
I ought to change out of
this cold. wet clothes.
I'm glad you've
returned. Adam.
Does Mr. Johns feel that
Mr. Windover will recover?
He does. now that
Mr. Windover is here.
He had begun making a turn
for the worst at that inn.
I. I shudder to
think of the outcome
if His Grace hadn't rescued him.
While His Grace may have
carried out the rescue.
your letter is the reason
we knew it was necessary.
We are all indebted
to you for that.
Mr. Windover is a good man.
Yes. he is.
Adam.
Mr. Johns believes
Harry will recover.
I suspect Harry is
too stubborn not to.
What is he in need of?
The apothecary is providing
powders and a tisane.
Aside from that. he says
Mr. Windover needs rest.
Then we will allow you
to see to his comfort.
I haven't had a chance
to check on Harry myself.
Bringing Harry here
was the best thing
you could've done.
Allowing him to sleep will
be the next best thing.
I suppose I should listen
when offered such sage advice.
I agree.
You've been out in
the cold all day. Adam.
You should get
some rest as well.
or you might very well
end up as ill as Harry.
I will have the kitchen
send you up a tray.
Adam?
Oh. Adam. you've
married a coward.
At least she doesn't snore.
Persephone!
Persephone- - Adam.
Uh. what?
Ridiculous.
I'm behaving like a
ridiculous lack-wit.
panicking over a dream.
-  Adam?
- What?
Harry seems a little
better this morning.
I am glad he is improving.
So am I.
Are you planning
on riding this morning?
I am.
I would
rather you didn't.
But I'm-
I would rather you didn't.
I won't if you really
don't want me to.
Good. I think it would
be best if you did not.
What in the blazes
is wrong with me?
Oh!
I get that a lot.
Ah. w-we've been
worried about you.
It's all been a
ploy to get attention.
Why were you so displeased
when you were
looking in the mirror?
Oh. it was nothing.
That wasn't nothing.
Do you think
I'm ridiculous?
Ah. lard buckets.
Adam's been talking
again. hasn't he?
He looked me over.
studying me very closely.
Then he said "Ridiculous."
He once described St.
James's Palace as ridiculous.
It's his favorite word.
He is so confusing.
All part of
his charm. Persephone.
How did he come to have
such extensive scars?
Adam's born with a stub
where his right ear
was meant to be.
A succession of surgeons
came to the castle over the
first few years of his life
attempting to find it.
The scars. then.
weren't the result
of an accident?
They were
attempting to "fix" him.
But. in the end.
he still has no ear.
his hearing is still a
little muffled on that side.
and he's been left scarred
in more ways than one.
You need to rest.
I'm fine.
And I won't keep you from it.
If there is anything
at all that he needs.
do not hesitate to ask.
Thank you. Your Grace.